And uh this actually will be uh funded
by the dividend that M&M earns from
Mindra Finance. In fact, only about
onethird of the dividend it earns from
Mindra Finance will be required for
funding this over the first 5 years. And
uh let me just spend a minute on our
vision for this joint venture. Our
vision is to be the number one life
insurer in rural and semi-urban India
because of the footprint that Mind the
Finance enjoys. Uh but that's not all.
uh we will be a significant player in
urban India as well and uh there we
would want to take a leadership position
in protection solutions one that uh
India is underpenetrated in today and uh
there are specific reasons why we feel
that we are well placed to be able to do
that despite the competition that we
have in the space today in urban India
let's talk about the opportunity
we Look at the protection gap in India.
India today is at 85% in terms of some
assured as a percentage of its GDP
as compared to 332% for Singapore, 250
for Japan, 250 for the US. But even
Malaysia and Thailand are significantly
ahead of us.
Demographics in India will be a key
driver of this play. Middle to high-
income households are growing rapidly
and they will be 50% of the population
by fiscal 30.
The wikis bharat goals outline insurance
for all by 2047.
The need for insurance is becoming even
greater in a world that's becoming more
uncertain, especially as disposable
income rises, awareness rises, and
security for family will always be a key
driver for people.
More importantly for rural and
semi-urban India, we see a significant
access gap.
Rural India 65% of population 45% of our
GDP but only 2% of life insurance
branches are in rural areas.
We looked at the critical success
factors in this industry.
The most important one is brand and
trust.
This is a business where a consumer
must trust the business to be able to
fulfill its promise to the consumer.
The control over distribution is
important which we have with Maidra
finance
very strong capability around
underwriting products
around reinsurance and this is something
that our partner brings. Manual Life is
uh one of the largest and among the most
respected insurers, life insurers in the
world and uh they're going to be our
equal partner and execution excellence.
This is something that you've seen from
all our businesses and uh it's now
something that uh we feel we can bring
to this business as well to be able to
deliver the promise that this business
has.
Let's talk about manual life. Uh it's a
leading Canadian life insurer.
More importantly in Asia, it's among the
top three insurers. Has large businesses
in uh a number of different countries in
Asia. Understands different markets
well. Has been very successful globally.
Uh 1.1 trillion in assets under
management, 36 million customers. Uh
understands agency very well, is a
leader in that space in many markets.
Has very strong reinsurance
capabilities. important from a capital
standpoint and is delivering consisting
consistent returns at 16.2% core ROE in
2024. Uh Manual Life is our partner for
the asset management business as well
and uh they're a wonderful partner. We
work very well together essentially as
one and uh this is in many ways an
extension of our partnership.
We talk about right to win. Why would a
customer buy from us?
And what you see on this page is a very
significant right to win from brand
trust to our distribution to treasury
relationships that can help unlock banka
van life brings in the product
underwriting reinsurance and agency
management expertise that it has uh and
collectively we've got a very strong uh
footprint around technology digital and
AI uh which are going to be critical for
this venture as well.
As I mentioned earlier, this is an
extension of a financial services
footprint. So from lending, asset
management, insurance, broking and now
life insurance. And uh this is one that
uh falls uh very much in our aspiration
for Mindra Finance uh to be the leading
financial services provider uh for
emerging India, for rural and semi-
urban India. So this is one that uh
really fits in very well with the
financial services footprint.
Our approach and uh while there is a lot
on this page, I'll just cover the key
points here. Uh once again to be the
number one life insurer for rural and
semi-urban India but also serve urban
customers and take a leadership role
there in protection solutions. So
protection is going to be a focus for us
but again not the only product. we will
have multiple products. Uh Minder
Finance distribution has 1,345
branches uh with very strong coverage in
rural and semi-urban India. Access to 25
lakh live customers uh which in itself
is a very strong base for this joint
venture to tap into. A premium agency
network is what we will build along with
a digital enabled ecosystem and uh these
will be uh factors that will help us
create a very sharp and focused strategy
and u be able to deliver on that promise
to create meaningful returns for our
shareholders.
As we talk about returns, um it's a it's
an area that obviously is very important
from our standpoint. Starting first with
the capital required as I mentioned
earlier, we expect to deploy about 250
crores a year for the first 5 years. A
total of 3,600 crores over 10 years.
This is the Mahindra commitment.
Similarly, Manual Life would uh put in
exactly the same amount of capital. And
with the global reinsurance expertise
that manual life has, it's possible that
this capital requirement might come down
as well. What we believe we can
accomplish with this is create a
business that in 10 years will give us a
valuation of 18,000 to 30,000 crores.
Now we do believe this is a conservative
set of numbers which we can achieve. Uh
there will be upsides to it and uh there
are a few upsides that we have not
factored in here. From a profit
standpoint though, this will be uh break
even only closer to year 10. Uh it's a
business that uh has uh certain dynamics
that will require time to break even
especially as you grow the business. uh
but valuation is based on the embedded
value and therefore that's how uh the
market would look at it and uh for us
it's not just about 10 years it's about
creating a business that's a very strong
and meaningful value ad for the group uh
over a longer time frame as well and
that's uh where this business will be
very well positioned and uh immediate
benefits to Mindra Finance uh from the
distribution that it will drive and
therefore the accretion on the ROA for
that
In summary, uh these are the uh four
areas that we talked about uh a year and
a half ago when we said that we will
look at one to two new areas and uh we
would look at do we have a strong right
to win, do we have a meaningful
potential, market leading returns and
ability to execute and very similar to
the SML acquisition uh where made that
to enhance a trucks and buses business
uh and we did it in a way where we felt
that it would add compelling value. Uh
it's actually adding more value than we
had even thought of at that time which
was a few months ago. Uh exactly like
that we feel that uh this venture will
also add meaningful value and we will be
able to come back and show that uh this
is something that will be a huge
accretion not just to minor finance from
an RO standpoint but to M&M shareholders
in terms of the value this creates. Uh
with that we will open it up for
questions.
>> Yes. Um please send your questions and
I'm getting the questions as we go
along. Anish the first question has come
from CNBC Yash Jen. Uh by when do you
expect to apply with U IDI and by when
do you expect to start operations and um
there are a couple more but let's start
with this because this is a question
that everyone's asked.
>> So we expect to apply for the license in
about 2 to 3 months and uh realistically
it will take 15 to 18 months uh for the
joint venture to start operations.
Okay, there there are many existing life
insurers where promoters are looking to
sell. Would it not would it not have
been a better strategy to acquire one of
those and get manual life in it? Also,
acquiring an existing insurer would have
given you some distraction strength.
>> Uh so we feel that we've got a very
strong proposition here with Mindra
Finance distribution with the customer
base we have not just in Mindra Finance
but also across the Mindra group. uh we
feel we can build a much stronger
business uh the way we've started it
it's also a lot more capital efficient
and one that will return a lot a much
greater returns for our shareholders.
Uh there's a question also on why choose
life insurance and not general. You sell
cars, tractors, the motor portfolio. Uh
that would have supported you've got you
would have got support from there.
>> Life insurance is underpenetrated today
and we see a tremendous opportunity here
and which is why we've started with
life. Uh if the insurance regulations
allow a composite license that could be
a potential upside for the JB and that's
something we will evaluate when that
happens and yes general is attractive as
well. uh but uh given the opportunity we
see that's very meaningful today uh
we've started with life
>> okay uh going to economic times now
shilp asked uh some of the questions are
repeat questions so I'm skipping those
but has the management team or CEO for
the new JV been identified will
leadership come primarily from Mahindra
manual life or external hiring
>> uh so all those details will follow uh
we have as you would expect a structured
approach to this and uh as soon as we
finalize those we will share those
details.
>> She's also asked what is the estimated
break even period for the life insurance
venture.
>> So again typically the break even period
is 10 to 12 years. Uh we feel confident
that uh we can improve on that. Uh but
uh I think once we start operations and
once we start seeing how things are
moving uh we'll have a better sense of
the exact time but uh at this point I
would just say that uh we will break
even much faster than uh what most most
others have done.
>> Sure. Uh now switching to NDTV profit
Vishnuat has asked questions on why
focus on semi- urban or rural locations
for this.
>> Uh so wish the uh focus on rural and
semi-urban comes from Mahindra finances
trends one second from the fact that uh
this is an underpenetrated area uh only
2% of life insurance branches are in
rural and semi-urban. It's also um an
area that's emerging very rapidly in
India. There is a significant amount of
uh wealth creation in rural and
semi-urban and uh we feel that we should
offer the set of products uh to that
area as compared to uh what they have
today. It doesn't say that we will not
focus on urban areas. We will and we
feel that we've got a compelling value
proposition there as well and uh that
will be focused on protection but we
will have a suite of products that
customers would need.
>> Okay. Anish one more question from ND
profit on how um how do you see uh the
recent buoy on because of the GST uh cut
from the government on life insurance.
Uh uh is the JV trying to capitalize on
that? uh so the JB will benefit from
that clearly and uh we are building this
for the long term uh in that sense uh
the momentum that we have today uh is a
very good place to start with
>> all right some questions from outlook
business how do you plan to tackle
competition in the sector which is
dominated by one state-owned insurer
>> uh we believe that uh this is a huge
space and uh there is room for many to
play uh as we've seen in the banking
sector as well and as we've seen with
NBFCs and uh the customer base we have
the connects we have the understanding
we have of markets uh is something
that's going to help us uh play in a
very meaningful play way here
>> okay moving to um business financial
expression has asked what is the
distribution synergy that you uh see for
the life insurance JV with other
businesses like Mindra Finance and
Mindra insurer insurance brokers
>> so MRA finance has 1,345 branches. Uh
Mind the Finance also has a corporate
agency license. Um and with some of the
work that's been done there, uh Mind the
Finance today is very well positioned to
now pivot to growth and u have some of
these businesses contribute meaningfully
uh to its bottom line and to its ROA and
therefore that's going to be a key
factor. But in addition to the maidro
finance distribution as well uh this
venture will look at banker uh there are
a couple of uh potential opportunities
we feel good about which we will
disclose as uh time goes on. Uh we will
look at uh agency because it's one area
where manual life is very strong at
manual life is also very strong in
affluent customers and products for
affluent customers. So serving urban
customers with agency networks and
manual life's expertise is going to be a
key area. And uh the digital channel
this is one where we bring a lot of
strengths in both from mind standpoint
and from manual life's global experience
and uh we aim to build a very strong
digital channel uh which will only grow
with time to come and therefore it's a
combination of Mindra Finance uh digital
banker and agency.
Uh Subra Panda from Business Standard
and Lindu Mishra, you have questions
around whether general insurance will be
the natural extension and do you plan to
get into it at what point?
>> Um yes, general insurance is a natural
extension.
We will look at uh this when the
insurance regulator allows composite and
we feel that that will be an upside that
we have uh to the numbers we've outlined
here
>> from money control. Hamsini is asked uh
how will this business be housed? Will
it be a subsidiary of Eminem Finance or
Eminem? Why should the business be
funded through M&M Finance's dividend?
What's your over overall strategy in
financial services given that Eminem
Finance um hasn't had a good patch for
almost two years now and you did
consider an investment in RBL banks a
few years back.
>> Uh so this is housed uh in Eminem
because of various reasons. uh
regulatory is one of them in terms of
how we've seen other uh groups and NBFCs
also uh take this path and it's
therefore the most expedient one from a
capital allocation standpoint we're
careful about how we spend capital and
which is where as this is an extension
of financial services effectively uh
we've earmarked uh one/ird of mandra
financ's dividend that we get uh for
this business and um RBL I know is a
favorite topic but as we've said earlier
that was uh uh primarily a treasury
investment. We've made a 63% return and
exited already.
>> From Mint, Anishika has asked you
mentioned using Mahindra Financ's
distribution to grow the insurance
business. The NBFC already has a
corporate agency license which currently
operates under open architecture. Is the
plan to sell or distribute only in-house
life products once the JV begins
operations?
uh from a regulation standpoint uh every
distributor has to uh work with multiple
companies and therefore Mahindra Finance
uh will follow uh that regulation and uh
it will offer products from other
insurers as well but uh the strength
that we see that Mindra Finance has and
the strength in products that can be
offered uh that are customized for
Minder Finance's customer base uh from
Mind Manuel live will make this a very
strong partnership.
>> Okay. Malvika from money control has
asked um what will be your initial
product focus protection plans, term
insurance or saving link policies?
>> Uh so we will offer all the products
that customers want but we feel that we
will have strengths in protection and
can create a very strong and compelling
offering and protection.
Okay, I think uh we've answered most
questions because a lot of them are
repeat of what you've already answered.
So um okay, there's one from NDTV profit
that's just come in as I spoke. Uh what
is the likely revenue profit
contribution from this JV business to
the consolidated business you expect
once the company breaks even in 10
years? [clears throat]
>> Uh so
we have outlined the business plan
that's something that uh we will
disclose uh as we go forward. uh with
analysts and investors as well. At this
point, what I would say is you're
building this business for meaningful
value creation opportunity uh that will
obviously be driven by profits. Uh but
specific numbers on profits is something
that uh we will disclose as we outline
the entire business plan uh uh at some
point in future.
>> All right, I hope we've uh captured all
the questions. Thank you everyone and
thank you Anish for taking us through
this um presentation and the Q&A.
>> Thank you.